

STEVE JONES



in/stevejones0



steve@stevejones.io



github.com/steve-jones

PROFILE



I'm a frontend software engineer passionate about creating awesome user experiences. My expertise is in translating user needs and stakeholder requirements to efficently develop products. I'm happiest doing UI engineering, data visualization, and attempting to discover the Balmer Peak.

EDUCATION



- M.S. Human-Computer Interaction 2016 2018 Georgia Institute of Technology
 - Management of Technology Graduate Certificate
 - Graduate Research Assistant
- B.S. Computer Science

2012 - 2016

University of Massachusetts - Amherst

- Concentration: Software Engineering
- Commonwealth Honors College

SKILLS



DEV

React | TypeScript | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Git | Design Systems | UI Component Libraries | Scrum

DESIGN

Wireframing | Rapid Prototyping | Graphic Design | User Centered Design | Figma | Sketch | Balsamiq

RESEARCH

Usability Testing | Task Analysis | Affinity Diagraming | Survey Design | Information Architecture | Design Sprints

EMPLOYMENT



SIMSPACE CORPORATION

JUNE 2018 - PRESENT

Senior Software Engineer II

- Frontend development: React, TypeScript, functional programming
- Implement features to support cyber range simulation training
- Led development of Monorail design system / component library

Dev Lead

- Lead agile cross-functional engineering team of 15 members
- Plan and implement features from user needs / stakeholder requirements
- Scrum Master

Engineering Manager

Dec 2020 - Present

- 6 FE direct reports - mentoring, career dev, performance reviews, etc.

DRAPER LABS

SUMMER 2017

UX Researcher & Sembler Associate - Intern

- Designed a tactical UI, designed & ran UX performance metric tests
- Conducted user tests to develop a set of heuristics for Microsoft Hololens
- Lead generation & needs assessment for tech startups

GAIN LIFE, INC.

SUMMER 2016

Product & UX Lead - Intern

- Developed product strategy for digital health coaching application
- Analyzed user needs & proposed, designed, implemented UX solutions

TIMETRADE SYSTEMS INC.

SUMMER 2015

UX Engineer - Intern

- Designed & developed TimeTrade's new Click To Check In web application
- Researched, designed, & implemented UX improvements to 4 apps

SEASCAPETECH

JULY 2010 - MAY 2015

Founder & President

- Created 30+ WordPress websites for clients in a variety of industries
- Managed a team of up to 3 developers

HYDROID INC.

SUMMER 2013

Web Development Intern

- Designed & developed Hydroid's company intranet
- Developed PHP plugin to manage of 100+ Windows Active Directory users

EBSCO INFORMATION SERVICES

SUMMER 2012

User Experience Intern

- Researched & proposed UX strategies for EBSCO Connection website
- Analyzed mouse tracking, heat maps, and web traffic data

PROJECTS

VISIT HTTP://STEVEJONES.IO FOR FULL PORTFOLIO



GRADUATE THESIS

MLB Statistics Visualization

- Design & development of a D3 InfoVis for MLB stats
- User testing and iterating to optimize efficiency of consuming data

UNDERGRAD HONORS THESIS

UX Implications of Google's Material Design Floating Action Button

- Designed & prototyped mobile app to perform user testing of the FAB
- Conducted 44 user tests and analyzed qualitative & quantitative results